法院院长被杀害了
The president of the court was killed.
这是什么? ！
What's this?!
我认为我们体面的法官参与了不体面的活动
I think that our honest judge was involved in not so honest actions.
- 谁杀了他? - 我不知道
- Who killed him? - I don't know.
他使我卷入了一桩肮脏的交易
He got me into a dirty business.
抗议书，抗议拆迁
The remonstrance. People against demolition.
法官，许可证怎么样了？
Judge, what about permits?
这是让一切合法化的唯一途径
That's the only way to make everything go legally.
米伦！
Milun!
丹尼洛 · 托马斯维奇，很高兴见到你，我们的新工作，海洛因
Danilo Tomasovich, nice to meet you. Our new job. Heroin.
你来制作，我来教你怎么做
You'll produce it, I will show you how to do it.
你为什么要拜访殿下？
Why are you visiting His Royal Highness?
诺维奇是来安排外交部长巴尔图先生的访问
Nowicki was arranging the visit of Minister of Foreign Affairs, Mr. Bartu,
并且试图说服国王
who was to convince Our Highness
应该承认苏联主权
that Yugoslavia should recognize the Soviet Union.
你还认为我们应该把
Do you still think that we should entrust
如此重要的任务交给贝尔格莱德组织？
such an important task to a Belgrade organization?
是的，一切都在控制之中
Yes. It's under control.
- 达维多维奇夫人 - 诺维奇伯爵
- Mrs. Davidovich. - Count Nowicki.
你真的什么都不知道？
You really don't know anything?
他们没告诉你是什么信息吗？
They didn't tell you what's in the message?
刺杀国王? ! 你什么意思？
Assassination of the king?! What do you mean?
一切都按照我们计划进行
Everything remains as we agreed.
你的工作是控制住IMRO
Your job is just to keep IMRO under control.
并且做好准备
And to be ready.
关于诺维奇伯爵的失踪你知道些什么？
What do you know about the disappearance of Count Nowicki?
我告诉你，她开始怀疑了
I'm telling you, she has some doubts.
似乎也和图勒组织有关
It seems to have something to do with The Thules as well,
而且穆斯塔法 · 戈卢布奇也以某种方式参与了这一切
and Mustapha Golubich is somehow involved in all that.
所有对政权的侵略活动
Every aggression towards the regime,
必须马上停止
must stop immediately.
黑手党，就是在这里成立的
The Black Hand. It was founded here.
我们用这把刺刀互相宣誓效忠
We swore allegiance to each other over this bayonet.
这是阿皮斯的刺刀
This is Apis' bayonet.
看看法官是不是被这个杀死的
Check to see if the judge was killed with this.
我们去了墓地... 有人偷走了遗骸
We went to the tomb and... Someone stole the remains.
这个名字被记录下来了，但是有人把它撕掉了
The name was recorded, but someone ripped off the page.
告诉他我知道名字了
Tell him I know the name.
站住！
Stop!
尸体在哪儿? ！
Where's the corpse?!
你什么意思? ！
What do you mean killed?!
他没有出席与殿下的会议
He didn't show up at the meeting with His Highness,
今天早上发现了他的尸体
and his body was found this morning.
你在开玩笑吗? ！
Are you kidding me?!
并非玩笑
Unfortunately, not.
跟踪他难道不是你的工作吗? ！
Was it your job to follow him?!
是的，但探员们也无法解释他是怎么消失的
Yes, and the agents can't explain how he disappeared.
他们护送他去了你们见面的酒店
They escorted him to the hotel, where he met you,
然后消失得无影无踪
and now he's lost without a trace.
听我说，乔洛维奇
Listen to me, Djolovich...
如果你是在陷害我...
If you set me up...
陷害你? ！
Set you up?!
你和那些和你有约定的人
You and those you made a pact with...
一定会被我搞死
will be fucked up.
什么约定? ！
What pact, for God's sake?!
但是如果你没有陷害我
And if you haven't set me up,
那你就是个彻头彻尾的白痴
but you're just a complete idiot,
那我别无选择只能牺牲我最亲密的伙伴
then I have no choice but to sacrifice my closest associate.
无论如何
In any case,
如果你不想被我搞死
if you don't want to be seriously fucked up,
那你就必须找到杀法国人的凶手
you must find the killer of that fucking Frenchman
越快越好
as soon as possible.
我和我的手下将尽我们最大的努力
I and the service will do our best.
滚出去！
Get out!
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第二季 第四集
BLACK SUN SEASON 02 EPISODE 04
早上好
Good morning.
我不记得上次睡得这么香是什么时候了
I don't remember when last I slept this well.
我们吃早饭吧
Let's have breakfast.
你早饭做得很好
You prepared this well.
你能做个好丈夫
You can get married.
你真的整晚都在沙发上吗？
Did you really spend the whole night on the couch?
那我该睡哪里? 睡在你旁边？
What was I supposed to do? Lie down next to you?
为什么不呢？
Why not?
又不是没睡过
It wouldn't be your first time.
这是你来找我的原因吗？
Is that why you came to me?
也许是吧
Maybe I did.
你想要什么？
What do you want?
- 什么意思? - 你还年轻...
- What you mean? - You are young...
漂亮，有钱，还聪明..
Beautiful, you have money, you are smart...
现在你结婚了
Now you're married.
是的，我真的很幸运
Yes, I was really lucky there.
那你要我这样的男人干什么？
What do you need a man like me for?
在这一切发生之后
After all this started happening,
我意识到我没有人可以求助
I realized I had no one to turn to.
我相信你和帕皮
I trust you and Papi.
其他人只是在利用我？
Everyone else is just using me?
我甚至无法想象
I couldn't even imagine
在这么多人中我会如此孤独
that I would be this lonely among all these people.
这是你的选择
That's what you chose.
我想我发现了
I think I've found out
穆斯塔法·戈卢比奇的藏身之处
where Mustapha Golubich is probably hiding.
在天文台
In the observatory.
那些共产主义者聚集在那里
Those communists gather there.
谢谢你
Thank you.
为什么穆斯塔法要杀诺维奇？
And why did Mustapha kill Nowicki?
因为诺维奇可能是个纳粹间谍
Because Nowicki was probably a Nazi spy.
纳粹最不想看到的
And the last thing the Nazis want
就是国王承认苏联主权
is for the King to recognize the Soviet Union.
现在他会怎么样呢？
And what will happen to him now?
我不知道
I don't know.
我什么都不知道，我不明白
I know nothing. I don't get it.
我们走
Let's go.
长官，什么事这么紧急？
Mr. Chief, what's so urgent?
我会告诉你的
I will tell you.
去停尸房
Drive to Babich, to the morgue.
是关于日尔诺夫的事吗？
Something about Zhrnov?
不，别管他妈的日尔诺夫了！
No, leave the fucking Zhrnov!
我们有紧急情况
We have an emergency.
这是我们之间的秘密
This is just between us.
秘密拜访国王的
The body of a French diplomat
法国外交官遗体被发现了
who was on a secret visit to the king was found.
事实上，他甚至没有机会去会见国王，因为他被杀了
In fact, he didn't even get to visit him because he got killed.
从今天早上开始就一片混乱，日夫科维奇给我打了三次电话
It's chaos since this morning, Zhivkovich called me three times.
有人会有麻烦，我不希望是我
Someone is going to get in trouble, and I don't want it to be me.
明白
Understood.
医生，我要跟你再说一遍刚才跟他们说的话
Doctor, I will tell you the same as my colleagues:
- 别告诉任何人 - 为什么？
- Don't tell anyone about this. - Why?
因为这个人很特殊
Because it is about a specific person.
就因为他是法国人
Just because he's French.
如果他是塞尔维亚人，他就不会那么特殊了
If he was a Serb, he would be less specific.
博士，放下政治和哲学
Doctor, let go of politics and philosophy,
从专业的角度，你能告诉我们什么？
what can you tell us from the professional side?
没什么，被杀了然后扔进河里
Nothing. Killed and thrown into the river.
好吧，我也可以得出这样的结论，我不是病理学家！
Well, I could conclude that too, and I'm not a pathologist!
首先他和某人摔跤
Okay. First he wrestled with someone,
显然对方更强壮更有技巧
obviously stronger and more skilful,
然后强壮的那个勒住了他
and then the stronger one started to strangle him,
然后用刀杀了他，把他扔进河里
then he killed him with a knife, and threw him into the river.
没什么神秘的
There is no great mystery here.
除了凶手是谁
Except for the fact who killed him.
好吧，胖子，那是你的工作
Well, fatty, you're going to have to deal with it.
不是我的
It's not my department.
说到这个，你知道这里有具尸体被偷了吗？
Speaking of which, do you know that a corpse was stolen from here?
什么尸体? ! 他在说什么？
What corpse?! What is he talking about?
那个阿瓦拉来的矿工！
That miner from Avala!
是的，我们听说了
Yes, we heard about it.
我查过了，巴雅克塔维奇的尸体被他的家人接走了
I checked, the body of Baryaktarevich was taken over by his family.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
没有我的签名谁也不能离开停尸房
No one can leave the morgue without my signature.
你签字了
Well, you signed it.
我? 你在说什么? ！
Me? What are you talking about?!
你签了字，我也查过了
You signed the warrant, I checked that too.
我看到你的签名了
Your signature is there.
巴比奇，你每天都喝得烂醉
Babich, you're so drunk every day
你连自己签没签字都不知道了！
that you don't even know your name anymore!
去死吧！
Go to hell!
我肯定我还没签...
I'm sure I haven't signed...
谁还在乎一个在日尔诺夫被疯子杀死的矿工? ！
Who gives a fuck for a miner who got killed by a lunatic on Zhrnov?!
为这个法国人写一份报告，要准确、漂亮
Write a report for this Frenchman, nicely and accurately.
我会派辆车送去大使馆
I'll send a car, we need to transfer it to the embassy and listen,
你从没见过这具尸体，明白吗？
you've never seen this corpse, okay?
我才不管他呢！
I don't give a fuck for him!
我想要那个阿瓦拉来的矿工，我还没有完成尸检
I want the miner from Avala, I haven't finished the autopsy.
有一些有趣的发现！
There are some interesting things!
什么发现？
What things?!
他前臂上有一个有趣的十字纹身
He had an interesting cross tattoo on his forearm.
去你的纹身！
Fuck your tattoo!
我还要因为纹身去挖一具尸体吗？！
Should I dig up a corpse because of your tattoo?!
去你妈的! 我们走，孩子们
Go fuck yourself! Let's go, kids.
快点，完成报告，我派一辆车过去！
Come on, finish it, I'm sending a car!
嘿，伙计们! 你们的旅馆不错
Hey, boys! That hotel of yours is good.
在纽约也没有比这更好的了！
There's no better in New York either!
- 很贵吗，日马罗? - 一般般
- Was it expensive, Zhmaro? - So-so.
那个大块头出了高价
The bighead put a high price,
但我们最终还是和解了
but we settled in the end.
- 达约! - 维利科！
- Dayo! - Velyko!
大学生活怎么样？
How's college going?
我按时通过了所有的考试
I pass all the exams on time.
- 太棒了! - 你好，达约？
- Bravo! - What's up, Dayo?
你在收债! 我不是叫你把他藏起来吗？
You're running a debt collection! Didn't I tell you to hide him?
不要带他一起走！
Not to take him with you!
贝尔格莱德到处都是暴徒，你还带他去！
Belgrade is full of thugs, and you took him!
- 他们抢劫了我，丹尼洛! - 闭嘴！
- They robbed me, Danilo! - Shut up!
这孩子需要大学毕业
The kid needs to graduate college.
成为一名律师，一名法官，或是一名部长
To be a lawyer, a judge, a minister.
不是像你这样的混蛋
Not a bastard like you.
- 我不是故意... - 你不是故意的！
- I didn't mean to... - You didn't!
如果你能动动脑子
If you were thinking,
我不会在监狱门口等你的！
I wouldn't wait for you in front of the prison!
- 典狱长人什么样?-我们的人他很厉害
- What's the warden like? - Our man, he's good.
明天送他一盒干邑白兰地
Send him a box of cognac tomorrow.
先生，这是您要的苹果
Sir, here are the apples you ordered.
- 是的 - 给你
- Yes. - Here you are.
谢谢
Thanks.
先生，太多了
Sir, it's too much.
钱永远不嫌多！
It's never too much money!
我的兄弟米伦会带着它，过来，把它放在你的背上！
My brother Milun will carry that. Come on, put it on your back!
米伦，你要带着它去哪儿？
Milun, where are you going with it?
把它放在车后座上
To put it in the back of the car.
不是在车里，是背在背上
Not in the car, carry it on your back.
你走在车后面，日马罗车开慢点
Walk behind the car and Zhmaro will drive slowly.
米里奇，我希望你找我到这个鬼地方来
Mirich, I hope there's something extremely significant
是有非常重要的事情
when you asked me to come in the middle of this hell I'm in.
我理解你的紧张
I understand your nervousness,
法院院长被谋杀可不是件小事
the murder of the president of the court is not a small thing.
这可不是小事米里奇
Not a small thing at all, Mirich.
所以不要愚弄我
So don't fool around and fool me.
我从来没有想到要愚弄你，对我来说，时间就是金钱
It never occurs to me to fool you. For me, time is money.
我想说”至于你”
I wanted to say "as for you",
但是我没说
but I bit my tongue.
无论如何，我认为我有足够的理由
In any case, I think I have a strong enough reason
把你从紧急重要的
to separate you from the important
调查活动中抽身出来
and much-needed investigation.
一个叫达尼洛 · 托马斯维奇的人..
A certain Danilo Tomasovich...
- 托马斯维奇? !-你认识他？
- Tomasovich?! - You know him?
他是从哪里来的？
Where did he come from?
简而言之，托马斯维奇也是一个来自纽约的美国黑帮分子
In short, Tomasovich is also an American mobster, from New York
他想跨越大西洋走私鸦片
and he would also like to smuggle opium across the Atlantic and,
据我所知，他想和我合作
as I understand it, he wants to offer me cooperation.
我们对此不感兴趣
We are not interested in that.
我早就猜到了
I could have guessed that.
托马斯维奇
Tomasovich...
是科罗沙克的人
is Koroshac's man.
他不是进监狱了吗？
Isn't he in custody?
米里奇，你生意做得很好，但你不懂政治
Mirich, your job is going well, but you don't understand politics.
- 他被软禁在家了 - 这样
- He is under house arrest. - Oh, yes.
他还担任了多年的内政部长
He was also the Minister of the Interior for years.
他一点也不天真
And he's not a naive man, at all.
他总是给我们制造麻烦
He causes us problems all the time.
那你有什么建议？
So what do you suggest?
在这种情况下，政府会特批
The service makes an exception in this case
而且不会要求分成
and will not ask for its percentage.
但是说到戈迪纳，米里奇先生
But with Godina, Mr. Mirich,
你只能和戈迪纳合作，我希望我说得够清楚了吧？
you must work only with Godina, I hope I was clear enough?
非常清楚，乔洛维奇先生
As clear as a day, Mr. Djolovich.
不过今天雾很大
A bit foggy day, though.
因为我不知道该拿那个黑山来的人怎么办
Because I don't know what to do with the man from Montenegro.
让他永远消失
Get rid of him. Forever.
越快越好
As soon as possible.
很明显，阿尔忒弥斯是因为那个名字
It is obvious that Artemiye was killed.
被杀死的
Because of that name.
凶手发现阿尔忒弥斯知道了这个名字
The killer found out that Artemiye knows the name.
现在，要么是阿尔忒弥斯自己告诉他
Now, either Artemiye told him,
或者是他...
or he was told by...
普尔沙？
Prsha?
该死的！
Well, damn it!
普尔沙，过来！
Prsha, come here!
普莱蒂科西奇，你一大早就开始喝酒
Pletikosich, you started drinking each and every morning.
别扯淡
Don't bullshit.
你跟神父说话的时候有人听见吗？
When you talked to the priest, did anyone hear you?
我不知道
I have no idea.
谁和你在一起？
Who was with you?
这个地方挤满了人，我不知道谁在听！
The place was full of people, I don't know who was listening!
当牧师告诉你他知道这个名字的时候
Who was next to you
谁在你身边？
when the priest told you he knew the name?
我在和迪米特里耶维奇谈话
I was talking to Dimitriyevich,
我们有事要谈
we had something to discuss.
我们站在那儿然后...
We were standing there, and...
等等，普尔沙，等等！
Wait, Prsha, wait!
当牧师告诉你这个名字的时候，迪米特里耶维奇就在你旁边？
Dimitriyevich was next to you when the priest told you about the name?
是的，牧师来的时候我正在和他说话！
Yes, I was talking to him when the priest arrived!
记我账上
Put this on me.
我宁可把它们扔进井里，也不愿记你账上！
Better to throw them in the well than put it on you!
改善和美化卡拉乔尔杰护城河
Improvement and beautification Karadjordje's moat
嘿，儿子！
Hey, son!
请坐，要喝点什么吗？
Take a seat. Do you want a drink?
不用了，谢谢
No, thanks.
- 来吧! - 不，我很好
- Come on! - No, I'm fine.
你为什么不在城里开一家办事处呢？
Why don't you open an office in town?
这里更需要我
I'm more needed here.
你为我这次旅行准备钱了吗？
Did you provide me with money for the trip?
学费
For schooling.
我真是个傻瓜！
What a fool I am!
我以为你至少会把这件事做对
I thought you'd at least do this right.
等等，拜托别走！
Stop, stop, stop! Please, stop!
孩子，我没有钱
Son, I don't have the money.
你可以杀了我，但我没有钱
You can kill me but I don't have it.
我很惭愧，但事实就是如此
I'm ashamed that I don't, but that's how it is.
我和最差劲的人渣合作赚钱，但是...
I teamed up with the worst scum to make money, but...
没赚到，坐下
...nothing. Sit down, please.
坐吧
Hey, take a seat.
再坐一会儿
Sit for a bit.
我已经...
I've done...
做了很多不好的事情
a lot of bad things in my life.
我和地痞人渣合作
I worked with the biggest human scum,
我当警察局长的时候收受贿赂
I took bribes while I was chief of police,
逮捕无辜的人
arrested innocent people,
讨好政客们...
flattered politicians...
最后落得如此下场
and I ended up in a place like this.
看到没? 在这该死的地方
See? In this damn place.
- 也许是你活该 - 是的
- You probably deserved it. - I did.
是的，但现在不重要了
I did, but it doesn't matter now.
你必须离开这里
It's important that you get out of here,
再也不会回来了
and not come back again.
忘记贝尔格莱德，忘记我..
Forget Belgrade, forget me...
开始新的生活
Start a new life.
如果是这样的话，我去奥布拉德那里拿钱
If so, let me take the money from Obrad.
那是不可能的！
That's out of the question!
我会给你筹到钱的，再给我几天时间
I'll find you the money, just give me a few more days.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
嘿！
Hey!
你怎么不敲门就进来了? ！
How did you get in without knocking?!
- 这个帅哥是谁? - 你没听见我说话吗？
- Who's this handsome guy, huh? - Can you hear me?
你怎么不敲门就进来了? ！
How did you get in without knocking?!
好吧，我给你带了个口信
Okay, I brought you a message.
- 出去! 出去! - 好的
- Get out! Out! - Okay.
“今晚10点来找我这很重要——维多杰”
"Come to me tonight at 10. It's important. Vidoje"
那是谁？
Who's that?
玛雅 · 达维多维奇
Maya Davidovich.
别问
Don't ask me anything.
我做了什么？
What have I done?
我会下地狱的
I'll end up in hell.
我不该听你的
I shouldn't have listened to you.
你带我进了这滩浑水
You got me in trouble.
我又拉着牧师下水，害他丢了性命
And I got him in trouble, sentenced him to death.
他什么都没做
He didn't do anything.
多好的一个人
Such a man!
凶手显然发现了
The killer apparently found out
牧师想告诉你
that the priest wanted to tell you the name.
凶手什么都知道
The killer knows everything.
总比你领先两步
He is two steps ahead of you.
牧师去酒吧找普尔沙
When the priest wanted to schedule a meeting with you
想和你约个时间见面的时候
and when he came to Prsha's bar,
迪米特里耶维奇和他在一起
Dimitriyevich was sitting with him.
那又怎样? ！
So what?!
迪米特里耶维奇听到牧师说想告诉你名字
Dimitriyevich heard that the priest wanted to tell you his name.
就算他听到了
Even if he did,
他根本不知道自己听到了什么
he wouldn't know what he heard.
他的事情太多了
He has too much on his plate.
这根本不算线索
You have nothing.
还有一件事
There is one more thing.
当我到那里的时候
When I arrived there,
阿尔忒弥耶神父还活着
Father Artemiye was still alive.
然后...他咕哝了几句
And... he muttered something,
我不确定，但他好像说了”兄弟”
I'm not sure, but it was like he said "brother."
兄弟？
Brother?
我不能发誓，但是...
I couldn't swear, but...
我肯定他说的是”兄弟”
I'm sure he said "brother."
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
我已经调查过了
I've checked this for you.
法官不是被这把刺刀杀死的
The judge was not killed with that bayonet.
凶手的刺刀更宽
The killer's bayonet was wider.
你从哪儿弄来的刺刀？
Where did you get the bayonet?
这已经不重要了
It doesn't even matter anymore.
接着调查法官，找出他的所有资料
Get back to the judge. Find everything about him.
在调查了
We're working on it.
我们正在调查法官
We're checking all judgements
过去五年的交易记录
and transactions in the past five years.
五年太短了，要调查更久之前的
That's a short period. It has to be longer.
你们要调查所有的记录
You need to check everything
从一战到现在
from the World War I to now.
- 特别是一战的时候 - 为什么？
- Especially the World War I. - Why?
我想知道
I would like to know.
新时代报
NEW AGE
法国外交官遇难
FRENCH DIPLOMAT FOUND DEAD
拉贾奇基先生
Mr. Rajachki.
阿里姆皮耶在哪里？
Where is Alimpiye?
请这边走
This way, please.
哦，亲爱的伯爵! 为什么这么匆忙？
Oh, dear Count! Why the hurry on this day?
你开始对男人感兴趣了？
You started to be interested in men?
那是诺维奇伯爵
That's Count Nowicki.
那晚他在你的俱乐部
He was at your club that night.
然后呢？
And?
他没出来
He didn't get out of it.
- 你怎么知道? - 我就是知道
- How do you know that? - I do.
因为是我带他来的
Because I brought him.
我负责照顾他
I took care of him.
我知道你是怎么做到的！
I see how you did it!
还有谁接触了他？
Who else was in charge of him?
尼娜小姐奉命把他带到包间
Miss Nina had an order to take him to the booth
会见玛雅 · 达维多维奇和她的丈夫
with Maya Davidovich and her husband.
- 真的? - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
尼娜！
Nina!
请过来
Please, come here.
- 什么事，老板? - 告诉我，这个人是谁？
- Yes, boss? - Tell me, who's this man?
- 我不知道 - 你从没见过他？
- I don't know. - You've never seen him?
我不确定，但我想我没见过
I'm not sure, but I think I haven't.
那你带谁去见玛雅 · 达维多维奇了
Who did you take to Maya Davidovich
在除夕夜？
on New Year's Eve?
不，不是他，是别人
No, not him. Someone else.
怎么会，当我带诺维奇来的时候? ！
How, when I brought Nowicki?!
好了，伯爵，请坐下
All right, Count, please sit down.
告诉我，另一个人长什么样？
Tell me, what did the other man look like?
很英俊，黑头发
Handsome, black hair,
很有绅士风度...
gentlemanly demeanour...
你从没见过这个人？
And you've never seen this man?
没有
No.
另一个人向我介绍他自己是诺维奇
The other man introduced himself to me as Nowicki,
我就照他们说的做了
and I did as I was told.
当然，请坐
Of course, of course. Sit down, please.
你总是听命行事
You always do as you are told.
- 没错 - 当然
- That's right. - Of course.
你永远不会对我撒谎？
And you would never lie to me?
绝不
No.
- 从来没有? - 从来没有
- Never? - Never.
你可以走了
You can go now.
你相信她
You trust her.
亲爱的伯爵
Dear Count, if there is loyalty,
我手下最忠诚的就是这个女人了
then it is in this woman.
这些年来她一直和我在一起，而且成长了许多
She's been with me all these years and she has grown.
明白吗？
Understand?
但也许忠诚是一种被高估的美德
But perhaps loyalty is an overrated virtue.
好的，请尽快告诉我
Okay, just let me know as soon as possible, please.
没错，波兹达 · 泽切维奇督察
That's right, Inspector Bozidar Zechevich.
谢谢
Thanks.
我一整天都在盘问他的手下
I've been questioning his officers all day.
怎么样，有什么发现吗？
How's it going, did you find anything?
是的
Yes.
首先，法官是在日尔诺夫遗址
First of all, the judge was on the Committee...
建造一个新的纪念碑的委员会成员
For the construction of a new monument on the site of Zhrnov.
这是一个很好的线索
That's a good connection.
- 干得好! - 是的，但这还不是全部
- Well done! - Yes, but that's not all.
他嗜赌如命
He's known as a passionate gambler.
且金额巨大
In large sums.
借债还债，等等
He borrowed, returned and so on.
他和有权势的人
These are the secret poker games
在地下赌场赌博
that all these powerful people play.
没有比这更糟的了
It couldn't be worse.
- 还有一件事 - 什么？
- There's one more thing. - What?
这些赌局是由我们的前任警长迪米特里耶维奇组织的
Those games are organized by our former chief, Dimitriyevich.
你的朋友塔尼也在帮他
And your friend Tane is helping him with it.
赌场的事情交给我吧
Leave those poker games to me.
你继续查他的文件
You keep digging through his papers.
下面是签名列表
Here is this list of signatures.
全部检查一遍
Check it all.
我有一种感觉，有什么重要的东西隐藏在那里
I have a feeling that something important is hidden there.
好吧
Okay.
嘿... 工作辛苦吗？
Hey... Working hard?
- 等等! - 怎么回事？
- Wait! - What's going on?
他们发的是俄罗斯小说吗！
Are they sending Russian novels?!
快点，把一切都告诉我！
Come on, tell me everything!
好的，就是这个！
Okay, here it is!
- 名字叫安东... - 好的
- Baptised name Anton... - Okay.
一个来自芝加哥的罪犯，籍贯伊斯特里亚
A criminal from Chicago, originally from Istria.
虽然是半意大利人
Although semi-Italian,
但他是帕维里奇乌斯塔沙组织的高层
he's at the top of Pavelich's Ustasha organization,
并且用毒品交易的利润
and finances their camps and terrorist actions
资助他们的营地和恐怖行动
with part of the profits from the drug trade.
- 你在听我说话吗? - 是的
- Are you listening to me? - Yes, I am.
居住地点呢？
And the place of residence?
那就好像有人找到了你的地址
Well, that would be as if someone found your address.
但是可以这么说
But it could be said that,
在札格拉布企图谋杀失败之后
after failed assassination attempt in Zagreb
他在意大利的时间较少，在维也纳的时间较多
he spends less time in Italy and more time in Vienna.
没有他在贝尔格莱德的消息吗？
There is no information that he was in Belgrade?
没有，怎么了？
No. Why?
因为他为军队工作
Because he works for the service.
好的，告诉我们在维也纳的人跟着他
Okay, tell our people in Vienna to follow him.
我会的
I will.
就这些吗？
Is that all?
不，我们才刚开始
No, we've just started.
该死! 拉下来！
Damn it! Pull it down!
- 好了吗? - 是的
- Finished? - Yes.
尼娜夫人来了
Mrs. Nina is here.
- 她说有急事 - 好的
- She said it's urgent. - Okay.
- 进来 - 对不起，出事了
- Come in. - Sorry. Shit happened.
说吧
Talk.
拉贾奇基在查法国人的事情
Rajachki is sniffing around the Frenchman.
穆斯塔法，做点什么吧，他会找到我的
Mustapha, do something, he will find me.
好了，冷静点，我们会解决的
All right, calm down, we'll work it out.
博雅纳！
Boyana!
这是我们的同志博雅娜，这是尼娜
This is our comrade Boyana, and this is Nina.
下午好
Good afternoon.
博雅娜今晚会去俱乐部
Boyana will come to the club tonight
你要把她介绍给拉贾奇基
and you will introduce her to Rajachki.
- 为什么是我? ! - 为什么是她？
- Why me?! - Why her?
我会解释的，你去吧，这里会有人看到你的
I'll explain. And you go, someone will see you here.
冷静点
Calm down.
别担心，我不会让你失望的
Don't worry, I don't let my people down.
马诺伊洛，送她出去
Manoylo, escort her.
这个法国人和我们有什么关系？
What has this Frenchman got to do with us?
法国人迫使你们的国王承认苏联主权
The French pressured your king to recognize the Soviet Union,
纳粹不喜欢这样
and the Nazis don't like that.
所以他们安排了为他们工作的诺维奇
So they set up Nowicki who works for them.
我们必须摆脱他
And we had to get rid of him.
为了摆脱他？
To get rid of him?
你杀了他？
You killed him?
这不关你的事
That's none of your business.
我需要你帮我安排拉贾奇基
I need you to set up Rajachki for me,
尽快到我们家来
and I need him in our place as soon as possible.
为什么？
Why?
我常说：“不问任何问题”
We said: "No questions asked".
- 为了...-谨慎起见
- Make sure... - To be discreet,
为俱乐部里的其他人打掩护
to provide coverage for everyone else in the club
除了拉贾奇基之外
and that no one, except Rajachki,
没有人知道我们在谈论什么，满意了吗？
knows what we talked about. Satisfied?
非常满意
More than satisfied.
奥地利 维也纳
VIENNA, AUSTRIA
他最后一次出现是在俱乐部
The last time they saw him getting into that club,
然后就他的尸体出现在河里
and then his body was found in the river.
诺维奇和我们合作很久了吗？
Has Nowicki been our brother for a long time?
是的
Yes.
我们能相信他吗？
Could we trust him?
他绝对是我们的关键人物
He was our absolute key person.
多亏了他，我们才知道了法国秘密警察在做什么
Thanks to him, we knew what the French secret police are doing.
难道法国人发现他为我们工作了吗？
Did the French perhaps discover that he worked for us?
不可能
Impossible.
他是第五局最重要的人物之一
He was one of the most important people of the Fifth Bureau.
巴尔图非常信任他
Bartu trusted him completely.
所以他才会被指派执行与亚历山大国王会面的任务
That is why this mission with the king Alexander was entrusted.
这样
Yes.
巴尔图是我们的眼中钉
Minister Bartu is a thorn in our side.
所以这一切才这么重要
That is why all this is so important.
我警告过你干涉巴尔干半岛的局势是很危险的
I warned you that interference of the Balkans would be a big risk.
你也同意只有这样..
And you agreed that only that way...
我们才不会被注意到
our role remains unnoticed.
是的
Yes.
但是你的人，第一步就搞砸了
But your people messed up on the first step.
我来处理
I'll handle it.
我们还有一个备用计划
We also have a backup plan.
我知道
I know.
但现在实施起来就难得多了
But now it will be much harder to implement it.
他们会更小心的
They'll be more careful.
最好尽快和诺维奇一起把这件事做完
It would be best to finish this thing with Nowicki as soon as possible.
你觉得这样对我更好吗？
You think it would be better for me?
这对我们大家都好
Better for all of us.
对你来说，这将是最好的选择
And for you, it would be the best.
这是什么意思? ！
What's this supposed to mean?!
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
我们不是说好了吗
Haven't we agreed
不能报道与诺维奇有关的新闻？
that there would be no words about Nowicki in public?
你说了很多事情，将军先生
You mentioned various things, Mr. General.
在各种场合
On various occasions.
我不知道为什么那样做会使我感到高兴
I don't know why that would oblige me in any way.
我们生活在一个自由的国家，不是吗？
We live in a free country, right?
听着萨夫科维奇
Listen Savkovich...
如果你认为
If you think that letting you shit about
由于德国国力强盛
the Führer as a great statesman
德国元首手腕强硬
and about Germany as a country of prosperity,
就意味着我们会害怕你的上司
means that we are afraid of your bosses,
或者你觉得我们没有证据证明你是德国间谍
or that we have no evidence that you are a German spy,
那你就大错特错了
you are seriously mistaken.
我真的不知道你是不是害怕我的老板
I really don't know if you're afraid of my bosses,
我不知道，我也不在乎
just as I don't know, nor do I care,
你挖出来关于我的事
what those rats of yours dug up about me.
但如果你跟我对着干
But if you go after me,
我向你保证
I guarantee you,
24小时之内，所有人都会知道
within 24 hours, the whole public will find out
你和副官们的奇怪狂欢
about your weird orgies with the adjutants.
既然你这么喜欢证据...
And since you love evidence so much...
给你
Here you are.
这可能是...新时代报的下一个头版
This could be, for example, the next cover of the New Age.
也许吧
Maybe.
如果没有其他事，就不再留你了
If that was all, I wouldn't keep you anymore.
哦，下午好，先生! 您想喝点什么？
Oh, good afternoon sir! What would you like to drink?
- 老样子 - 这位女士呢？
- Give me mine. - And for the lady?
别问我，我又不是她
Don't ask me, I'm not a lady.
我要白兰地，双份
I'll have brandy. Double.
稍等
Wow! In a minute.
你已经成为贵妇了
You've become a lady.
上校的妻子
The colonel's wife.
只是白兰地不适合这位贵妇
It's just that brandy doesn't go with the lady.
- 干邑白兰地更合适 - 饶了我吧
- Some cognac suits better. - Give me a break.
给你！
Here you are!
先生要格瓦斯，女士要双份白兰地
Kvass for the gentleman and double brandy for the lady.
这种白兰地是塔尼酿造的，他有一种特殊酿造工艺
Tane made this brandy, he has a special way of preparation.
- 首先他去掉了... - 普尔沙！
- Firstly, he takes the... - Prsha!
拿个烟灰缸过来
Bring an ashtray.
我要离开维多杰
I'm leaving Vidoje.
孩子们都长大了，去了寄宿学校
The children are big, they went to the boarding school,
他再也没有理由软禁我了
he has nothing to hold me for anymore.
我要去巴尼亚卢卡的阿姨家
I'm going to my aunt's in Banja Luka.
她孤身一人
She is alone and old,
得有人照顾她
someone needs to take care of her.
我不需要上校先生的任何东西
I don't need anything from Mr. Colonel.
好了
There.
这就是我想告诉你的
That's what I wanted to tell you.
然后你应该知道你要做什么了
And you see what you'll do.
如果我们之间还有什么的话
If there is still something between us.
如果你厌倦了那个假惺惺的已婚女人
And if you got bored of that smirk who also got married.
心甘情愿，不像我，被人欺骗
Willingly. Not like me, by being tricked.
但就我看来，她已经被原谅了
But she is forgiven, as far as I can see.
我不想为她感到难过
I didn't want to feel sorry for her.
- 为了你... 我做到了 - 真的吗？
- And for you... I did. - Oh, really?
你老了，但仍然是个骗子
You grew old and remained a liar.
- 我不想吵架 - 我也不想
- I don't want to argue. - Neither do I.
你的白兰地很棒
Your brandy hit me.
祝你健康
Stay healthy.
你也是
You too.
我该付你多少钱？
How much do I owe you?
免单！
You owe me nothing!
再见，普尔沙
Goodbye, Prsha.
再见
Goodbye.
如果你这么说的话
If you say so.
普尔沙！
Prsha!
给我也来一杯双份白兰地
Give me that double brandy, too.
哦，天哪！
Oh, Jesus!
长官，你找我吗？
Mr. Chief, did you call me?
坐下，泽切维奇
Sit down, Zechevich.
- 这是哪一年的? - 1921年
- What year is this from? - From 1921.
- 这是唯一的一份? - 是的
- This is the only copy? - Yes.
谢谢，你可以走了
Thank you. You can go.
泽切维奇！
Zechevich!
你来这儿多久了？
How long have you been here?
三年，在战场上一年多
Three years. More than a year on the field.
你做得很好，每个人都称赞你
You are doing well, you are good, everyone praises you.
看来你和斯坦科相处得不错
I see you get along with Stanko.
是的，普莱蒂科西奇督察教我很多东西
Yes, Inspector Pletikosich can teach me a lot.
当然，但他有时候独自行动
Of course, but he sometimes works on his own,
这对一个警察来说可不是好事
and that is not good for a police officer.
塔纳西耶维奇也是这样，你听说过他吗？
Tanasiyevich was the same. Have you heard of him?
当然，整个警局仍然在谈论他
Of course, the whole Glavnjacha still talks about him.
这我可不知道
I didn't know that.
他们见过面吗？
Do they see each other?
据我所知没有
Not that I know.
泽切维奇，我想让你帮我个忙
Zechevich, here's what I wanted.
关注普莱蒂科西奇
Pay attention to Pletikosich.
他是个好警察，但很固执
He's a great cop but he's stubborn,
这是个麻烦的案子，时机很不好
and this is a troublesome case, troublesome time.
他不应该因为他的固执而惹上麻烦，明白吗？
He shouldn't get in trouble for his stubbornness, understand?
我不明白
I don't.
我是说，我需要知道他在做什么
I mean, sometimes let me know what he's doing,
他要去的地方... 特别是他要去见塔纳西耶维奇
where he's going... especially if he's seeing Tanasiyevich.
长官
Mr. Chief,
恕我直言，我不会..
with all due respect, I will not...
不，你不会的
No, no, you won't.
这只是个小小的预防措施，别担心
It's just a small precaution, don't worry.
别担心! 去吧! 你可以走了
Don't worry! Come on! You can go now.
南斯拉夫王国 保罗 · 贝尔格莱德王子的住所
THE RESIDENCE OF PRINCE PAUL BELGRADE, KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
将军先生，保罗王子在等你
Mr. General, Prince Paul is waiting for you.
科斯马奇? ！
Kosmach?!
我不是驱逐你到斯洛文尼亚吗？
Didn't we repel you to Slovenia?
王子雇了我
The prince hired me.
科罗沙克帮你安排的？
Koroshac arranged that for you, huh?
他还没有死于赫瓦尔河上的葡萄酒吗？
He hasn't died from that wine on Hvar yet?
所以你没有线索？
So you have no clues?
你不知道是谁杀了他
You don't know who killed him.
我甚至不知道动机是什么
I don't even know what the motive was.
除非有人想阻止巴尔图部长来访
Unless someone wanted to prevent Minister Bartu from visiting.
这是一个合乎逻辑的解释
That is a logical explanation.
但是巴尔图不会因此取消他的访问...
But Bartu won't cancel his visit because of that...
还有一件事
There's something else.
南斯拉夫承认苏联主权
Is the Yugoslav recognition of the Soviet Union
真有那么重要吗？
really that significant?
这是目前欧洲这一地区的核心外交问题
It is currently the central diplomatic issue in this part of Europe.
王子，恕我直言...
Prince, allow me to say that...
真不敢相信国王已经准备
I can't believe the king is ready
去帮助那个红色的渣滓
to give a hand to that red scum.
甚至不是因为法国
Not even because of France.
共产党并不是唯一的威胁
Communists aren't the only ones threatening the world as we know it.
有时候你不得不和人渣合作来战胜更大的邪恶
Sometimes you have to work with scum to defeat the greater evil.
这就是法国的逻辑
That's French logic.
我们也要遵循这个逻辑吗？
And we will follow that logic?
再看吧，国王还没有做出任何决定
We'll see, the king hasn't made any decision yet.
我们需要法国，但他们也需要我们
We need the French, but they need us too.
我们一定要小心
We definitely need to be careful.
我弟弟现在有很多敌人
My brother has many enemies at the moment,
所以我们要找出杀害诺维奇伯爵的凶手和动机
that's why we need to find out who killed Count Nowicki and why.
并且要尽快
And to do it as soon as possible.
我会尽力的
I will do my best.
奇妙的幻觉世界
WONDERFUL WORLD OF ILLUSION
纽约有这样的俱乐部吗？
Are there any clubs like this in New York?
纽约什么都有
There is everything in New York.
你自己看吧，我们完事后我带你去
You'll see for yourself, I'll take you when we're done here.
- 真的吗? - 是的，我必须这么做
- Really? - Yes, I have to.
这些人会宠坏你的
These people will spoil you here.
但你不是去那里的俱乐部，而是去大学学习
But you're not going to clubs there, but to graduate from college.
先生们
Gentlemen.
欢迎! 这边请
Welcome! This way.
你好! 贝尔格莱德的纽约！
Well, hello! New York in Belgrade!
或者应该说“科拉辛”？
Or it's better to say "Kolashin"?
（阿尔巴尼亚语）
Njegushi.
哦，伟大的祖国，还有意大利熏火腿
Oh, homeland of the great Njegosh. And great prosciutto.
哟，返璞归真了
Oh, back to the roots.
普莱蒂科西奇督察！
Inspector Pletikosich!
普尔沙！
Prsha!
给我们的警官一杯白兰地，再给我也来一杯
Give a brandy to our Inspector, and pour me one, too.
塔尼，悠着点，你要喝趴了！
Tane, slow down a little, you'll fall under the bar!
别废话了，快倒酒！
Cut the crap, just pour it!
怎么样? 警官，你发现什么了吗？
And? Inspector, did you find anything?
没有
No.
已故的法官在迪米特里耶维奇的赌场赌博吗？
Did the deceased judge gamble at Dimitriyevich's place?
一直都是
All the time.
他输了很多钱
And he was losing a lot of money.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
- 他那晚有参加赌博吗? - 有
- Did he gamble that night? - Yes.
我当时不在场，但我听说他们吵起来了
I wasn't there but I've heard that he was yelling and arguing.
- 和迪米特里耶维奇? - 是的
- With Dimitriyevich? - With him, too.
请让我搜查一下赌场
Please let me check the casino.
我不会向任何人透露地点
I won't reveal the location to anyone.
无意冒犯，但绝不可能
No offence, but no way.
如果你需要调查什么，我可以帮你看看
If you need anything, I can check it out.
普莱蒂科西奇，我很高兴你能来
Pletikosich, I was so glad you came,
我们像以前一样聚在一起
we all got together like we used to,
但当他开始喝酒时
but when he starts drinking,
一切都毁了！
everything goes to hell!
你一定知道有个地方现在开门了
You must know a place that's open now,
我不能再听他逼逼了
I can't listen to him anymore.
我唯一能想到的地方
The only place I know is open now
是你的老朋友修道士的俱乐部
is the club of your former friend Monk.
这是个有趣的想法
That's an interesting idea.
我们去会会他吧！
Let's go to ask him something!
- 你是认真的吗? - 当然！
- Are you serious? - Sure!
我们去毁了他的夜晚吧
Let's ruin his night.
普莱蒂科西奇，至少你是清醒
Pletikosich, at least you are sane,
他喝成这样不要带他去那里
don't take him there in this condition.
滚犊子，傻逼，去睡觉吧
Come on, you cunt, go to sleep.
别担心，我会照顾好他的
Don't worry, he's in good hands!
我...
Me...
我是傻逼？！
Me cunt?!
- 晚上好，先生 - 晚上好
- Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
- 你想要什么? - 一杯气泡酒谢谢
- What would you like? - A spritzer, please.
打扰下! 维多杰先生来了吗？
Excuse me! Did Mr. Vidoje come?
- 没有 - 谢谢
- No, no. - Thank you.
我受够了
I'm done.
祖斯卡明天会来把房间打扫干净
Zuska will come tomorrow to clean everything up.
我明天一早就走
I'm leaving at dawn tomorrow.
你知道这张桌子是怎么来的吗？
Do you know where this table is from?
- 这有什么关系? ! - 有关系
- Why does it matter?! - It does.
我父亲在维也纳给我母亲买了这张桌子
My father bought this table in Vienna for my mother...
- 因为她想要 - 维多杰！
- Because she wanted it. - Vidoje!
我给了你我能给的一切
So I gave you everything I could,
我给了你房子，孩子，所有的一切
I gave you this house, I gave you children, everything.
但那还不够，我配不上你
But that wasn't enough. I wasn't good enough for you.
维多杰，别说了！
Vidoje, come on!
我给了你你想要的一切...
I gave you everything you wanted...
- 但这还不够 - 你喝醉了！
- But it wasn't enough. - You're drunk!
- 不! - 维多杰，你喝醉了！
- No! - Vidoje, you're drunk!
- 不，还不够 - 你喝醉了！
- No, it's not enough. - You are drunk!
我是喝醉了！
I am drunk!
那又怎样? ！
So what?!
你为什么在乎？
Why do you care?
你走了
You left.
我不知道还有这样的地方
I didn't know places like this existed.
你应该去看看巴黎的俱乐部
You should see clubs in Paris.
保持警惕
Keep your eyes open.
晚上好，欢迎！
Good evening, welcome!
- 晚上好 - 欢迎
- Good evening. - Welcome.
- 在这儿等我 - 等等！
- Wait for me here. - Hold on!
瑞士的年轻女士拉杰基伯爵到了
Count Rajachki, the young lady from Switzerland has arrived.
来自 La Roche 公司
From La Roche company,
她想见你，我刚才告诉过你
she wanted to meet you, I told you a moment ago.
博雅纳小姐，拉贾奇基伯爵
Miss Boyana. Count Rajachki.
晚上好
Good evening.
托马斯维奇先生，你是一个非常有说服力的人
Mr. Tomasovich, you are a very convincing and charming man.
我们为什么要合作？
Why would we work together?
因为不像其他的混蛋
Because, unlike these jerks here,
你是唯一一个展望未来的人
you are the only one looking to the future.
这是我听说的
That's what I heard.
你没听错
You heard right.
我们的未来会是什么样的呢？
And what would our future look like?
我不知道会是什么样子
I don't know what it would look like,
但我知道是有利可图的
but I know it's profitable.
海洛因
And it's called heroin.
真的吗？
Really?
海洛因？
Heroin?
- 纯吗? - 世界上最纯的
- Clean? - The cleanest in the world.
我想你已经知道了
I think you already know that we have
我们和德国的欣德医药公司有很好的关系
excellent relations with the German Hindelpharm.
我们为什么要换合作伙伴呢？
Why would we change the winning team?
是的
Yes.
那么您是否知道目前正在制定一项新的、更严格的
Are you aware that a new, much stricter Geneva Convention
关于鸦片贸易的日内瓦公约？
on the opium trade is being prepared?
我还没有听到最重要的部分
I haven't heard the most important thing.
我不明白
I don't understand.
第一批货之前付两百万
Two million before the first shipment.
两百万什么？
Two million of what?
美元，托马斯维奇，你来自美国
Dollars, Tomasovich, you came from America.
一百万
One million.
第一批货的70%
And 70% of the first shipment.
我不想浪费时间
And only because I don't want to waste time.
你知道两个聪明人相遇会发生什么吗？
Do you see what happens when two smart men meet?
我不知道谁能比在国内的日内瓦
I don't know who could handle the Geneva Convention
更好地处理《日内瓦公约》
better than the one in Geneva at home.
更不用说我那个朋友...
Not to mention that my friend...
有权签订合同
has the authority to celebrate signing a contract
并支付佣金
with a commission.
真的吗？
Really?
你知道这个协议
Do you understand that this agreement
应该保持绝对的谨慎吧？
should remain an absolute discretion?
那是当然
That goes without saying.
尼娜小姐会发给你秘密会面的邀请
You will receive an invitation for a discreet meeting from Miss Nina.
怎么样？
How did it go?
非常成功
It was very useful.
我希望我们的同志会满意
I hope that our beauty will be pleased.
- 拜托! - 尽管...
- Come on! - Although...
他并不是一个难以取悦的人
He's not a hard man to please.
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好！
- Good evening! - Good evening!
需要位子吗？
Do you need a table?
是的，而且视野要好
We do, with a good view.
哦，博雅纳在这！
Oh, Boyana is here!
我们有位子了，谢谢
We have a table, thanks.
你来这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
博雅纳，晚上好！
Boyana, good evening!
晚上好！
Good evening!
这两个人在这里干什么? ！
What are these two doing here?!
妮娜，过来！
Nina, come here, please!
这两个人来这里干什么? ！
What are these two doing here?!
我怎么能不让警察探长进来呢？
How can I not let a police inspector come in?
马上把他们赶走
Get them out now.
不，让他们在这吧
No, let them.
最好还是盯着他们
It's better to keep an eye on them.
你总是对的
You are right, as always.
他给了我们一个很有吸引力的提议
He made us a fascinating offer.
我低估了他
I underestimated him.
真可惜! 真可惜！
What a pity! What a pity!
我们该怎么办？
What should we do?
这笔交易继续
The deal remains.
小佩塔怎么样了? 他长大了吗？
How's little Petar? Has he grown?
大男孩了! 但是普尔沙宠坏了他
Big boy! But Prsha spoiled him.
我得去看看他
I have to come see him.
- 这位小姐... - 丹妮卡
- And Miss... - Danica.
你结婚了吗？
Are you married?
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
凭着美貌，你可能已经结过上千次婚了
By beauty, you could be married a thousand times already,
但是这么年轻... 我不这么认为
but by youth... I don't think so.
年轻似乎占了上风
Youth seems to have prevailed.
这个好解决
Well, we could fix that.
不要在意，塔尼总是心直口快
Don't pay attention, Tane was always direct.
而且坚持不懈
And persistent.
丹尼卡小姐是做什么的？
And what does Miss Danica do?
我在大学的一个研究中心工作
I work at a research centre at the university.
- 在森林里? - 是的
- In the forest? - Yes.
我听说那里发生了有趣的事情
I heard that interesting things happen there.
是的
It's true.
- 你可以带我去一次 - 塔尼
- You could take me once. - Tane.
不幸的是，只有获得许可才允许进入
Unfortunately, entry is allowed with permission only.
我让她也带我去，但很不幸...
I told her to take me too, but unfortunately...
- 禁止进入 - 塔尼！
- The access is forbidden. - Tane!
- 是吗? - 看那两个人
- Yes? - Look at those two.
还有右边
One on the right...
还有一个就在我们身边
And one is here with us.
- 米里奇先生! - 什么事？
- Mr. Mirich! - Yes?
你要走了吗？
Are you leaving already?
很晚了，我们得回家了
It's late, we have to go home.
- 你不看演出了吗? - 改天吧
- You won't see the show? - Some other time.
真遗憾，但我真的很开心
Too bad. But I'm really happy
为了我们未来的合作
for our future cooperation.
- 谢谢，明天见 - 好的，晚安！
- Thanks, see you tomorrow. - Sure, good night!
再见！
Goodbye!
在这里等我们
Wait for us here.